YOUSSEF MOURAFFA

MASTER'S GRADUATE IN DATA PROCESSING | DEEP LEARNING, CNN, NLP ENTHUSIAST

+49 176 25075666 | MOURAFFAYOUSSEF@GMAIL.COM | KIEL, GERMANY

OBJECTIVE

With a Master's degree in Data Processing, specializing in deep learning, I bring a blend of theoretical expertise and practical application in Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing. My hands-on experiences, including a Google-prize-winning internship with Orange Morocco and a role as a Data Scientist at AUV Team Tomkyle, have honed my skills in real-world data science applications.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Tech Skills:

- Python, C/C++, MATLAB
- TensorFlow, PyTorch
- OpenCV, YOLO, NLTK
- scikit-learn, Keras, NumPy, Pandas
- Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Git, Docker, Linux
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- SQL/MySQL

Hard Skills:

- Data Exploration and Visualization
- Data Mining
- Model Development and Evaluation
- Feature Engineering
- Probability and Statistics
- Predictive Modeling
- Natural Language Processing (NLP)
- Computer vision (CNN)

Soft Skills:

- Communication
- Collaboration
- Problem-Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Interpersonal Skills
- Communication
- Time Management

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Intern | AUV Team Tomkyle

Mar 2023 - Dec 2023, Kiel, Germany

- Addressed computer vision challenges in underwater environments, improving image analysis from sonar and camera data for aquatic exploration and real-time object detection.
- Engaged in researching and testing methods to quantify the similarity between two distinct annotations.

IoT Intern | Orange Morocco in partnership with Google & EY

Jul 2022 - Sep 2022, Rabat, Morocco

- Awarded Google's Favorite Award among 40 international projects.
- Successfully transformed project ideas into reality with a motivated and dedicated team.

Bachelor Thesis A | Information Laboratory at Hassan 2 university

Apr 2021 - Jun 2021, Casablanca, Morocco

 Programmed a comprehensive system for monitoring and optimizing electrical consumption, featuring real-time cost tracking.

EDUCATION

Erasmus Exchange Program

Mar 2023 - July 2023, Kiel, Germany

• Completed advanced courses in Deep Learning, contributing to academic projects that emphasized teamwork and interdisciplinary collaboration.

Master's Degree in Data Processing

Sep 2021 - Mar 2023, Casablanca, Morocco

- Courses in advanced mathematics, machine learning, computer vision, natural language processing, programming languages, operating systems, the Internet of Things (IoT), and Microcontrollers.
- Actively involved as a trainer in the IoT Club at Hassan II University of Casablanca.

Licence in Electronics Engineering under the LMD system

Sep 2017 - July 2020, Casablanca, Morocco

• Developed a diverse technical foundation, including Internet of Things (IoT), statistical analysis, programming, physics, and core engineering principles.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Artificial Creativity: Generating Realistic Anime Characters with Generative Adversarial Networks
- Real-Time Object Detection with YOLOv5: A Streamlit-Powered Visual Experience
- NLP for Efficient Literature Skimming: Replicating Neural Networks for Medical Paper Abstract Classification
- Unleashing Gemini's Potential for Interactive AI Applications with Large Language Models (LLM)

CERTIFICATIONS LANGUAGES

DeepLearning.AI: Natural Language Processing

• Udemy: Deploy Data Science Web Apps with Streamlit

Udemy: MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence

• IBM: Python for Data Science, AI & Development

MathWorks: MATLAB Onramp

English: AdvancedFrench: AdvancedArabic: Native

German: Basic Knowledge

ONLINE PRESENCE

Portfolio <u>GitHub</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>